Henry A. Grunwald Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Correspondence, 1943-2006 (Box 4-26)
  - Individuals
    - Peterson, Patti, 1988-1989 (Box 14)
    - Peterson, Peter and Joan Ganz Cooney, 1991-2004 (Box 14)
    - Pickering, Thomas, 1997 (Box 14)
    - Pierrepont, Nancy, 1993-2001 (Box 15)
    - Pirie, Robert S., 1998-2002 (Box 15)
    - Plate, Thomas, 1990-1997 (Box 15)
    - Porterfield, Christopher, 1990-2003 (Box 15)
    - Posner, Irina, 1997-2000 (Box 15)
    - Prager, Karsten and LaVerne, 1989-2004 (Box 15)
    - Prawy, Marcel, 1990-2002 (Box 15)
    - Prendergast, Curtis, 1995-2004 (Box 15)
    - Price, Charles, 1988-2004 (Box 15)
    - Prowda, Judith, 2000 (Box 15)
    - "R" miscellaneous, 1985-2005, (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Rabbani, L., 2004 (Box 15)
    - Rabl-Stadler, Helga, 2000 (Box 15)
    - Rauch, Rudolph S., 1994-2003 (Box 15)
    - Ravenel, Jean-Charles de, 1990-2004 (Box 15)
    - Reagan, Nancy, 1987-2004 (Box 15)
    - Ribikoff, Casey, 1998-2004 (Box 15)
    - Roberts, Jean, 2002 (Box 15)
    - Rockefeller, David, 2002-2004 (Box 15)
    - Rohatyn, Elizabeth and Felix, 1990-2003 (Box 15)
    - Rosen, Clare Mead, 1986-2005 (Box 15)
    - Rosenblatt, Roger, 1988-2001 (Box 15)
    - Rosenthal, Abe and Shirley, 1987-2003 (Box 15)
    - Rosenthal, Felix, 1993-2002 (Box 15)
    - Ross, Roberta, 1990-1996 (Box 15)
    - Rubin, Albert L., 1988 (Box 15)
    - Rudel, Julius, 1982 (Box 15)
    - Ruttenberg, Janet, 1981-2004 (Box 15)
    - Ryan, Pat, 1989-2000 (Box 15)
    - Rybakov, Anatoli, 1992-1993 (Box 15)
    - "S" miscellaneous, 1982-2005, (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Sailer, John, 1993 (Box 16)
    - Sanders, Pamela, 1992-1993 (Box 16)
    - Sayers, Mark, 2004 (Box 16)
    - Sayn-Wittgenstein-Sayn, Marianne, Princess of, 1989-2002 (Box 16)
    - Schambeck, Herbert, 2001-2002 (Box 16)
    - Schlesinger, Arthur, 1997-2002 (Box 16)
    - Scholz, Kurt, 1990-1999 (Box 16)
    - Scholz-Strasser, Inge, 1993-1994 (Box 16)
    - Schreiber, Erwin, 1993 (Box 16)
    - Schreier, Felicity, 1992-2002 (Box 16)
    - Schussel, Wolfgang, 2002 (Box 16)
    - Schwartz, Casey, 1999 (Box 16)
    - Schwarz, Egon, 1991-2004 (Box 16)
    - Schwarzenburg, Kari, Prince, 1987-1988 (Box 16)
    - Scowcroft, Brent, 1988-1993 (Box 16)
    - Segall, Harold A., 1992-1998 (Box 16)
    - Seitz, Raymond G. H., 1991-1992 (Box 16)
    - Shapiro, Robert, 2002-2004 (Box 16)
    - Sheed, Wilfrid, 2002-2004 (Box 16)
    - Shriver, Sargent, 1988-1989 (Box 16)
    - Sider, Don, 1988 (Box 16)
    - Sills, Beverly, 1984-2004 (Box 16)
    - Simpson, Hope, 2003 (Box 16)
    - Sitrick, James B., 1988-1997 (Box 16)
    - Smith, Liz, 1990-2005 (Box 16)
    - Smith, Richard, 1992-2002 (Box 16)
    - Smith, Stephen G., 1989-2003 (Box 16)
    - Snyder, Joseph and Ann, 1991-2001 (Box 16)
    - Solomon, Solange, 2001-2004 (Box 16)
    - Soltner, Andre, 1987-1995 (Box 16)
    - Sonnenfeldt, Richard, 1988-2003 (Box 16)
    - Spielvogel, Carl, 1991-1993 (Box 16)
    - Stanton, Domna and Frank, 2000-2002 (Box 16)
    - Stark, Bruce, 1990-2002 (Box 16)
    - Steinberg, Gayfryd and Saul, 1997-2000 (Box 16)
    - Steinberg, Kathryn, 2002-2005 (Box 16)
    - Steinert, Eleanor H., 1981-1997 (Box 16)
    - Stephenson, Michele, 1987-1992 (Box 16)
    - Sterling, Bryan B., 1983-2004 (Box 16)
    - Stern, H. Peter, 1999-2003 (Box 16)
    - Stevens, Mark and Annalyn Swan, 1994-2004 (Box 16)
    - Stevenson, Nikolai, 1996-2000 (Box 16)
    - Stolley, Richard, 1989-2003 (Box 16)
    - Stolz, Einzi, 1988-1998 (Box 16)
    - Strauss, Robert, 1991 (Box 16)
    - Strauss, Robert D., 1988 (Box 16)
    - Strauss, Walter A., 1986-1993 (Box 16)
    - Styron, William and Rose, 1987-2000 (Box 17)
    - Sulzberger, Arthur and Jean, 1994-2003 (Box 17)
    - "T" miscellaneous, 1988-2004 (Box 17)
    - Talbot, Strobe, 1988-2004 (Box 17)
    - Tapert, Annette, 1994-1999 (Box 17)
    - Tasman, Alice and William, 2001-2004 (Box 17)
    - Taubman, A. Alfred, 2000-2001 (Box 17)
    - Temmer, Sylvia, Stephen, and Georges, 1988-1998 (Box 17)
    - Thomas, Evan, 1999 (Box 17)
    - Thompson, Benjamin and Jane, 1980-2002 (Box 17)
    - Traubner, Richard, 1981-1999 (Box 17)
    - Tuerk, Helmut, 1997 (Box 17)
    - "U" miscellaneous, 1990-2004 (Box 17)
    - Ungeheuer, Barbara, 1991-2001 (Box 17)
    - "V" miscellaneous, 1988-2003 (Box 17)
    - Vanden Heuvel, William, 1992-2003 (Box 17)
    - Vega, Marylois, 1994-2000 (Box 17)
    - Vidal, Gore, 1997 (Box 17)
    - Vital, David, 2002-2005 (Box 17)
    - Vranitsky, Franz, 1997-2002 (Box 17)
    - "W" miscellaneous, 1982-2005, (2 folders) (Box 17)
    - Walderdorff, Johannes, 1994-2002 (Box 17)
    - Walker, Diana and Mallory, 1989-2003 (Box 17)
    - Wallace, Mike and Mary, 1981-1992 (Box 17)
    - Walters, Barbara, 1983-2005 (Box 18)
    - Warner, Elizabeth, 1997-1998 (Box 18)
    - Ways, Connie and Brigid, 1995-2003 (Box 18)
    - Wedgwood, Ruth, 1990-1997 (Box 18)
    - Weidenfeld, George, 1985-1997 (Box 18)
    - Weinstein, Harvey, 1997-1998 (Box 18)
    - Weiser, Peter and Elly, 1988-2003 (Box 18)
    - Westin, David and Sherrie, 2000-2004 (Box 18)
    - Whitehead, John C., 1997-1998 (Box 18)
    - Wilde, James, 1999-2005 (Box 18)
    - Wilson, Don, 1989-1992 (Box 18)
    - Wilson, Pamela, 2002-2004 (Box 18)
    - Wolf, Milton A., 1994-2001 (Box 18)
    - "X, Y, Z" miscellaneous, 1987-2004 (Box 18)
    - Zarem, Bobby, 1981-1987 (Box 18)
    - Zilk, Helmut, 1990-1994 (Box 18)
  - Organizations
    - American Austrian Foundation
      - Ambassador Milton A. Wolf Fellowship, 1994-2004, (6 folders) (Box 18)
      - Board of Trustees, 1990-2004 (Box 19)
      - Duke University Visiting Media Fellows Program, 1995-1996 (Box 19)
      - Salzburg Cornell Seminars, 1993-2002, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - American Friends of the Salzburg Easter Festival, 2000-2005 (Box 19)
    - American Society of Magazine Editors awards, 1992-1997, (2 folders) (Box 19)
    - Austrian Cultural Institute, 1990-1995 (Box 19)
    - Austrian Consulate General, 2002 (Box 19)
    - Austrian organizations, miscellaneous, 1990-2002 (Box 19)
    - Center for Communication, 1988-2001, (5 folders) (Box 19)
    - Century Association, 1980-2003, (5 folders) (Box 20)
    - Columbia University Graduate School of Journalism, New York, N.Y., 1992-1995 (Box 20)
    - Committee to Protect Journalists, 1996-1999 (Box 20)
    - Council on Foreign Relations
      - Foreign Affairs magazine, 1990-2001 (Box 20)
      - General, 1988-2003 (Box 20)
      - Haas, Richard, 1996 (Box 21)
      - Media project, 2000 (Box 21)
      - Nominations, 1988-2004 (Box 21)
      - North Atlantic Treaty Organization trip, 1991 (Box 21)
      - Post-Communist Eastern Europe discussion group, 1990-1991 (Box 21)
      - Public Diplomacy Roundtable, 2001-2002 (Box 21)
      - Reich, Jens, 1990 (Box 21)
      - Schussel, Wolfgang, 2001 (Box 21)
      - Skubiszewski, Krzyztof, 1990 (Box 21)
      - Studies program, 1996 (Box 21)
      - Task force on public diplomacy, 2002, (7 folders) (Box 22)
      - Task force on U.S. Middle East policy and the peace process, 1997 (Box 23)
      - Term member program, 1999-2001 (Box 23)
      - Vranitzky, Franz, 1990-1996 (Box 23)
    - Freedom Forum Media Studies Center, 1993-1999 (Box 23)
    - Goethe House, New York, N.Y., 1991 (Box 23)
    - Henry R. Luce Foundation, 1993-2004 (Box 23)
    - Heritage Foundation, 1992 (Box 23)
    - Independent Journalism Foundation, 1991-1995 (Box 23)
    - International Press Institute, 1990-1997 (Box 23)
    - International Rescue Committee, 1997-2005, (3 folders) (Box 23)
    - Knickerbocker Club, 1995-2004 (Box 23)
    - Library of America, 1996-1997 (Box 23)
    - Lighthouse International, 1996-2005, (3 folders) (Box 24)
    - Living Landmarks, 2003 (Box 24)
    - Martha's Vineyard Tabernacle Restoration Fund, 1999 (Box 24)
    - Mauerbach Benefit Sale, 1996 (Box 24)
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1996-2000 (Box 24)
    - Metropolitan Opera Guild, 1990-2005 (Box 24)
    - Millenium Committee of New York, 2000 (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous organizations, 1983-2003 (Box 24)
    - Moscow Press Center, 1993-2001 (Box 25)
    - New York Public Library
      - General, 1991-2003 (Box 25)
      - Helen Bernstein Award for Excellence in Journalism, 1993-1997, (4 folders) (Box 25)
    - New York University, 1990-2004, (3 folders) (Box 25)
    - Nixon Center for Peace and Freedom, Washington, D.C., 1995 (Box 25)
    - Opera News, 1990 (Box 25)
    - Pen American Center, 1999-2000 (Box 25)
    - President's Commission on White House Fellowships, 1993 (Box 26)
    - Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty Fund, 1992 (Box 26)
    - Reynolds Society Dinner and Achievement Awards, 1997-1998 (Box 26)
    - Richard Tauber Centennial, 1991 (Box 26)
    - Rogosin Institute, 1987-1994 (Box 26)
    - Rotunda Club, 1991-1994 (Box 26)
    - Royal Society for the encouragement of Arts, Manufactures and Commerce, 1992-1999 (Box 26)
    - Salzburg Seminar, 1993-2004 (Box 26)
    - Schepens Eye Research Institute, 1999-2002 (Box 26)
    - Schumpeter award, 1994 (Box 26)
    - Shubert Archive, 1993-1994 (Box 26)
    - Smithsonian Institution Archives of American Art, 1998 (Box 26)
    - Special Olympics, 1991-1993 (Box 26)
    - Theodor Herzl symposium, Vienna, Austria, 1993-1996 (Box 26)
    - UNESCO, 1990 (Box 26)
    - World Press Freedom Committee, 1990 (Box 26)
- Writings, 1940-2004 (Box 27-88)
  Articles, books, journals, proposed projects, speeches, and student writings.
  Grouped alphabetically by format and by publication or title therein.
  - Articles
    - American Heritage, "A New Tribalism," 1995 (Box 27)
    - Biographical features, 1986-1996 (Box 27)
    - Clips and notes, 1948-1993, undated (Box 27)
    - Esquire, "Katharine Graham: Washington's Other First Lady," 1997 (Box 27)
    - Foreign Affairs
      - "Foreign Policy Under Reagan II," 1984 (Box 27)
      - "The Post-Cold War Press," 1993 (Box 27)
    - Fortune, "New Challenges to Capitalism, 1990, (2 folders) (Box 27)
    - Glamour, "Who Loves Salinger?," 1963 (Box 27)
    - Horizon
      - "An Address From the Class of 1944," 1963 (Box 27)
      - "Andre Malraux: The Gods in Art," 1958 (Box 27)
      - "A Bernstein Suite," 1959, (2 folders) (Box 28)
      - "The Disappearance of Don Juan," 1962, (4 folders) (Box 28)
      - "From Eden to the Nightmare," 1963 (Box 28)
      - "J.D. Salinger: 'He Touches Something Deep in Us,'" 1962 (Box 29)
    - Life, "Judaism," 1955 (Box 29)
    - Media Studies Journal, "Opening Up 'Valleys of the Uninformed,'" 1993 (Box 29)
    - Miscellaneous essays, 1992-1993 (Box 29)
    - Money, "A Letter to My Granddaughter," 1992 (Box 29)
    - New York Magazine, "How to Save the City," 1990 (Box 29)
    - New York Times, "Liberte, Oui. Egalite? Fraternite?," 1989 (Box 29)
    - New Yorker, "Losing Sight," 1996-2000, (3 folders) (Box 29)
    - Newsweek, "Remembering Katharine Graham," 2001 (Box 29)
    - Opera News, "Count Maritza," 1995 (Box 30)
    - Research not used, 1995-1999 (Box 30)
    - Suddeutsche Zeitung, "A Future for United Europe?," 1994 (Box 30)
    - Time
      - Clinton foreign policy, 1993 (Box 30)
      - "Home Is Where You Are Happy," 1985 (Box 30)
      - "The Conservatives' Morning After," 1992 (Box 30)
      - Lee Kuan Yew interview, 1997 (Box 30)
      - "Letter to an Isolationist," 1993 (Box 30)
      - "Memorandum to Perot Supporters," 1992 (Box 30)
      - "Memorandum to Woodrow Wilson," 1994 (Box 31)
      - "The Second American Century," 1990, (4 folders) (Box 31)
      - "When Peacekeeping Doesn't Work," 1995 (Box 31)
      - "Who Cares About a Free Press?," 1995 (Box 31)
      - "The Year 2000," 1992-1997 (Box 31)
    - Wall Street Journal
      - "A Backward Glance From the Animal-Rights Future," 1990 (Box 31)
      - "Charles and Diana: Not an Operetta," 1996 (Box 32)
      - "Crossover: 'Rent' and 'La Boheme'," 1996, (2 folders) (Box 32)
      - "Jane Austen's Civil Society," 1996 (Box 32)
      - "The Language of Art: Papa Knew Best," 1998 (Box 32)
      - "The Lure of the Rings," 2002 (Box 32)
      - "The Power of the Word," 1999 (Box 32)
      - "Remembering Alger Hiss," 1996 (Box 32)
      - "Salzburg's Other, Quieter Festival Thrives," 2000, (2 folders) (Box 32)
      - "Salzburg's Other, Quieter Festival Thrives," 2000 (Box 33)
      - "A Symphony's Enduring Power to Move Us," 2001 (Box 33)
      - "Vladimir Nabokov, American," 1997 (Box 33)
      - "A World Without a Country?," 2000 (Box 33)
    - Washington Post, "We Can Manage Without an Enemy," 1990 (Box 33)
    - Whittle Communications, "How to Handle Europe," 1991, (3 folders) (Box 33)
    - Whittle Communications, "How to Handle Europe," 1991, (3 folders) (Box 34)
  - Books
    - One Man's America
      - Acknowledgments, 1996 (Box 34)
      - Anchor Books, 1997-1999, (2 folders) (Box 34)
      - Bibliography, 1996 (Box 34)
      - Book parties, 1996-1997 (Box 34)
      - Books sent, 1996-1997 (Box 34)
      - Correspondence, 1996-2000, (6 folders) (Box 35)
      - Doubleday, 1990-1997 (Box 35)
      - Endorsements, 1996 (Box 36)
      - "How to Become an American," 1988-1991 (Box 36)
      - Lynn Goldberg Communications, Inc., 1996 (Box 36)
      - Manuscript drafts, 1996, undated, (5 folders) (Box 36)
      - Manuscript drafts, undated, (2 folders) (Box 37)
      - Miscellaneous book notes, 1996-1997 (Box 37)
      - Outline, 1989-1995 (Box 37)
      - Paperback edition, 1996-1997 (Box 37)
      - Pictures, 1996-1997, undated, (5 folders) (Box 37)
      - Publicity, 1997, (4 folders) (Box 38)
      - Reviews, 1997 (Box 38)
      - Research files
        - Affirmative action, 1982-1985 (Box 38)
        - Allende, Salvador, 1971 (Box 38)
        - Appointment as ambassador to Austria, 1987 (Box 38)
        - "America Through Europe's Eyes," undated (Box 38)
        - "The American Century," 1941 (Box 38)
        - American history textbook, 1941 (Box 38)
        - "American Renewal," 1981-1995 (Box 38)
        - "The American Woman," 1952 (Box 38)
        - Anson, Robert Sam, 1987-1994 (Box 38)
        - Auchincloss, Douglas, 1943-1981 (Box 38)
        - Balfour, Honor, 1945-1972 (Box 38)
        - Bel Air symposium, 1972 (Box 38)
        - Bell, Daniel, 1975 (Box 38)
        - Bell, James, undated (Box 38)
        - Berlin, Irving, 1994-1995 (Box 38)
        - Bermuda writers' conference, 1968, (4 folders) (Box 39)
        - Bernstein, Leonard, 1957-1990 (Box 39)
        - Bicentennial, 1975-1987 (Box 39)
        - Bloch, Felix, 1995-1996 (Box 39)
        - Book contracts, 1961-1964 (Box 39)
        - Book outlines, 1994 (Box 39)
        - Book themes, 1988 (Box 39)
        - Brubeck, David, 1954 (Box 39)
        - Cables (telegrams), 1988 (Box 39)
        - Cambridge seminar, 1974, (3 folders) (Box 40)
        - Career chronology, 1951-1994 (Box 40)
        - Carter, Jimmy, 1976-1977 (Box 40)
        - Cave, Ray, 1976-1995 (Box 40)
        - Chambers, Whittaker, 1949-1991, (2 folders) (Box 40)
        - Clurman, Richard M. and Charley Mohr, 1963 (Box 40)
        - Corporate editor, 1976-1995 (Box 40)
        - Council on Foreign Relations Commission on United States Policy Toward the Soviet Union, 1980-1995 (Box 41)
        - Daughters of the Heart of Mary, 1956-1961 (Box 41)
        - Davis, Joanna and Peter, 1961-1974 (Box 41)
        - Democratic National Convention, 1968 (Box 41)
        - Donovan, Hedley, 1977-1979 (Box 41)
        - de Havilland, Olivia, 1994 (Box 41)
        - Deus, Alice, 1981-1982 (Box 41)
        - Discover magazine, 1976-1995 (Box 41)
        - Editing, 1971-1980 (Box 41)
        - Editor in Chief, 1978-1987, (2 folders) (Box 41)
        - Eisenhower campaign train, 1952 (Box 41)
        - Europe, 1951-1952 (Box 41)
        - "The Fanciest Dive," 1986 (Box 41)
        - Feminism, 1952 (Box 41)
        - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1993 (Box 41)
        - Fonda, Jane, 1994 (Box 41)
        - Focus interviews, 1975 (Box 41)
        - Ford, Gerald, 1975 (Box 42)
        - Freud, Sophie, 1993 (Box 42)
        - Friday magazine closing, 1974 (Box 42)
        - Gaines, Jim, 1986-1987 (Box 42)
        - Gardner, Ava, 1951 (Box 42)
        - Gillespie, Marcia, 1971 (Box 42)
        - Gorbachev, Mikhail, 1985 (Box 42)
        - Graham, Billy, Rev., undated (Box 42)
        - Graves, Ralph, 1968-1995 (Box 42)
        - Grunwald, Henry, retirement, 1987 (Box 42)
        - Haaren High School, New York, N.Y., 1926-1990 (Box 42)
        - Haig, Alexander M., 1984 (Box 42)
        - Hammerstein, Oscar, II, 1945-1960 (Box 42)
        - Hayden, Tom, 1976 (Box 42)
        - Heiskell, Andrew, 1980 (Box 42)
        - Hiland, Bruce, 1995 (Box 42)
        - Herzstein, Robert Edwin, 1993 (Box 42)
        - Hiss, Alger, 1991-1992 (Box 42)
        - Holt, Estelle, undated (Box 42)
        - Hook, Sidney, 1949-1990 (Box 42)
        - Hughes, Robert, 1975-1991 (Box 42)
        - Irving, Clifford, 1972 (Box 42)
        - Jefferson, Thomas, 1976-1977 (Box 42)
        - Judaism, 1953-1955 (Box 42)
        - Kennedy, Robert, 1968 (Box 42)
        - Kent State University, Kent, Ohio, 1970 (Box 42)
        - Kissinger, Henry, 1973-1995 (Box 43)
        - Koch, Edward, 1986 (Box 43)
        - Kollek, Teddy, 1975 (Box 43)
        - Kopkind, Andrew, 1994 (Box 43)
        - Kosinski, Jerzy, 1973-1988 (Box 43)
        - Kraft, Joseph, 1975 (Box 43)
        - Krauthammer, Charles, 1983 (Box 43)
        - Law and journalism, 1973-1974 (Box 43)
        - Leadership, 1974-1979 (Box 43)
        - Lee, Alwyn and Essie, 1966-1993 (Box 43)
        - Lerner, Alan Jay, 1960-1961 (Box 43)
        - Life research and development report, 1963 (Box 43)
        - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1973 (Box 43)
        - Luce, Henry, III, 1995 (Box 43)
        - Luce, Henry Robinson, 1953-1995 (Box 43)
        - Maass, Meta, 1945-2001 (Box 43)
        - Magazine business, 1975 (Box 43)
        - Magnuson, Ed, 1976-1995 (Box 43)
        - Mailer, Norman, 1968-1992, (2 folders) (Box 44)
        - Malraux, Andre, 1955 (Box 44)
        - Managing editor, 1963-1983, (2 folders) (Box 44)
        - Marx, Karl, 1948 (Box 44)
        - Matthews, Thomas S., 1949-1991 (Box 44)
        - McManus, Jason, 1975 (Box 44)
        - Meetings, 1976-1986 (Box 44)
        - Miscellany, 1986-1989 (Box 45)
        - Mohr, Charlie, 1982 (Box 45)
        - Moynihan, Daniel P., 1975 (Box 45)
        - "Mr. Strauss Goes to Boston," 1938-1945 (Box 45)
        - Nargolwala, Joe, 1991 (Box 45)
        - Neils, Patricia, 1995 (Box 45)
        - News service chronology, 1972-1977 (Box 45)
        - New York University, 1941-1990 (Box 45)
        - Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1990-1993, (2 folders) (Box 45)
        - Notes, miscellaneous, circa 1980s (Box 45)
        - Phi Beta Kappa, 1957 (Box 45)
        - Phillips, B. J., 1994 (Box 45)
        - Picture Week, 1985-1986 (Box 45)
        - Playboy, 1993 (Box 45)
        - Portugal, 1975 (Box 45)
        - Press speeches, undated (Box 45)
        - Procedures, 1976 (Box 45)
        - Progressive education, 1928-1977 (Box 45)
        - Reagan, Ronald, 1980 (Box 46)
        - Refugees, 1992 (Box 46)
        - "Requiem in Leningrad," undated (Box 46)
        - Research and development memoranda, 1962-1963 (Box 46)
        - "The Role of Congress: a Study of the Legislative Branch," 1973, (2 folders) (Box 46)
        - Roman Catholic Church, 1993 (Box 46)
        - Sauk Centre, Minn., 1995 (Box 46)
        - Schultz, George P., 1995 (Box 46)
        - September 1940, 1983 (Box 46)
        - Sharon, Ariel, 1985-1995 (Box 46)
        - Shaw, John, 1944 (Box 46)
        - Shenker, Israel, 1994 (Box 46)
        - Sidey, Hugh, 1995 (Box 46)
        - Simenon, Georges, 1957-1958 (Box 46)
        - Stalin, Joseph, circa 1950s (Box 46)
        - Steinem, Gloria, 1964 (Box 46)
        - "Summing up 1975" (Box 46)
        - Santa Barbara symposium, 1982 (Box 46)
        - Talbott, Strobe, 1983 (Box 46)
        - Texas, 1975 (Box 46)
        - "Thought and Religion During the Past Hundred Years," 1956 (Box 46)
        - Tillinger, Eugene, 1952 (Box 46)
        - Time, inc. annual reports, 1980-1984 (Box 47)
        - Time, inc. chronology, 1977-1993 (Box 47)
        - Time, inc. creative conference, Bermuda, 1977 (Box 47)
        - Time, inc. miscellany, 1944-1991, (2 folders) (Box 47)
        - Time, inc. sex discrimination complaint, 1971 (Box 47)
        - Time anniversaries, 1973-1998 (Box 47)
        - Time employee strike, 1976-1995 (Box 47)
        - Time modern living section, undated (Box 47)
        - Time "Update on America," 1977 (Box 47)
        - Toynbee, Arnold J., 1954 (Box 47)
        - TV Cable Week, 1982-1983 (Box 47)
        - Vallee, Rudy, 1972 (Box 47)
        - Vienna reunion, 1983-1988, (3 folders) (Box 47)
        - Vietnam, 1965-1969 (Box 48)
        - Waldheim, Kurt, 1994-1995 (Box 48)
        - Wallace, George, 1994 (Box 48)
        - The Washington Star, 1981 (Box 48)
        - Watergate, 1973-1974, (3 folders) (Box 48)
        - Ways, Max, undated, circa 1950s (Box 48)
        - Wilde, James, 1989-1993 (Box 48)
        - Wilson, Sloan, 1958 (Box 48)
        - Worker priests, circa 1950s (Box 48)
        - Women's liberation, 1970 (Box 48)
        - "The Year 2000 project," 1987 (Box 48)
        - Younger generation, 1951-1989 (Box 48)
      - Rosen, Clare Mead
        - Baby boomers and the 1950s, 1993 (Box 48)
        - Beats, 1993 (Box 48)
        - Clurman, Richard, 1993 (Box 48)
        - Comments, 1991-1992 (Box 48)
        - Economics of the 1950s, 1993 (Box 48)
        - Friedrich, Otto, 1993 (Box 48)
        - Fuerbringer, Otto, 1994 (Box 48)
        - Gart, Murray, undated (Box 49)
        - Intellectuals, 1993 (Box 49)
        - Interviews, 1992 (Box 49)
        - Loeb, Marshall, 1995 (Box 49)
        - Magnuson, Ed, 1992-1994 (Box 49)
        - Miscellany, 1992-1994 (Box 49)
        - Religion, 1993 (Box 49)
        - Southern tour, undated (Box 49)
        - Watergate, circa 1970s (Box 49)
      - Travel
        - Africa, 1966-1977, (2 folders) (Box 49)
        - Chronology, undated (Box 49)
        - Europe, 1951-1979, (7 folders) (Box 50)
        - Europe, 1981-1987, (8 folders) (Box 51)
        - Far East, 1969-1987, (7 folders) (Box 52)
        - Logs, 1969-1987 (Box 53)
        - Mexico and Panama, 1983 (Box 53)
        - Middle East, 1969-1975, (4 folders) (Box 53)
        - Middle East, 1978-1986, (6 folders) (Box 54)
        - Miscellany, 1969-1987 (Box 54)
        - Newstour itineraries, 1969-1985 (Box 55)
        - Pacific Rim, 1985, (2 folders) (Box 55)
        - Report on America newstour, 1971, (2 folders) (Box 55)
        - Southeast Asia, 1964 (Box 55)
        - Soviet Union, 1963 (Box 55)
        - Soviet Union, 1987 (Box 56)
        - Summaries, 1969-1987 (Box 56)
        - Time/Update on America, 1981, (2 folders) (Box 56)
        - United States, 1974-1975, (2 folders) (Box 56)
    - A Saint More or Less
      - Additions, 2000-2003 (Box 56)
      - Alphabetical subjects, 1999-2001, (4 folders) (Box 57)
      - Avrillot, Barbe-Jeanne, Madame Acarie, 1999-2002 (Box 57)
      - Berulle, Pierre de, 2000-2001 (Box 57)
      - Bibliographies, undated (Box 57)
      - Book parties, 2003-2004 (Box 57)
      - Books sent, 2004 (Box 57)
      - Bosse, Abraham, 2000 (Box 57)
      - Butler, Shane, 1998-2001 (Box 58)
      - Calvinism, undated (Box 58)
      - Catholicism, 1996-2002 (Box 58)
      - Catholic League, 1999 (Box 58)
      - Catholic mass, undated (Box 58)
      - Cheney, Paul
        - Digital research files, 1999-2000, mss85225_142_004
        - Paper research files, 1999-2000 (Box 58)
      - Copy edits, 2003, (2 folders) (Box 58)
      - Correspondence, 1996-2004, (2 folders) (Box 59)
      - Demonical possession, 1999-2000 (Box 59)
      - Digital drafts and research files
        - Sept. 2001, mss85225_142_005